Guide to the Chancellor of the University of Pittsburgh, Wesley W. Posvar, Administrative Files, 1967-1991 UA.2.10.1967-1991
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Academic Year 1978/79, XII.
  - Academic Programs, 1978-1979; 1.0.
    - Faculty of Arts and Sciences (FAS), 1978-1979; 1.4.
      - FAS - General (Box 2, Folder 1.4)
        Paintings for the University's Collection Exhibition the portrait of Hugh Brackenridge by Gilbert Stuart; The Symposium on Renaissance Art, June 1979; Planning document for the Department of Physics and Astronomy and Proposal for Financial Support for Research and Graduate Program Development in Physics and Astronomy; American Political Science Association inviting the University to join the Policy Studies Organization (PSO), May 5, 1979; Approval of Undergraduate Majors in Applied Mathematics, Statistics, and Religious Studies; Facilities Planning has advised that the Langley Aerodrome has arrived at Benedum Hall, January 29, 1979; Application for Biomedical Research Support Grant, December 19, 1978; Budget adjustments for 1978-1979; General State Authority approves funding request for reconstruction of Langley Hall; The Hersh Collection, November 1978; The Center for Philosophy of Science Annual Report for the 1977-1978 Academic Year; IREX Research Exchange Programs, September 13, 1978; FAS Policy on Low Enrollment Courses; The possibility of a chair for the study of Politics and Business, August 7, 1978; Appointment of Dr. Chien Ho, Distinguished Service Professor of Biological Sciences, July 1978; Meeting Concerning Trip to Asia, August 18, 1978; FAS Departments as of July 1, 1978; and Booklets on Asian Studies and the UP Gallery.
      - FAS - Board of Visitors (Box 2, Folder 1.4a)
      - Chemistry (Box 2, Folder 1.4b)
      - Biological Sciences (Box 2, Folder 1.4c)
      - Music (Box 2, Folder 1.4d)
      - English (Box 2, Folder 1.4e)
      - Marina v. N. Whitman (Box 2, Folder 1.4f)
      - Theatre Arts and Renovation (Box 2, Folder 1.4g)
      - Slavic Chair and Studies (Box 2, Folder 1.4h)
      - Classics (Box 2, Folder 1.4i)
      - American Experience (Box 2, Folder 1.4j)
      - American Political Science Review and Association (Box 3, Folder 1.4k)
      - Sociology (Box 3, Folder 1.4l)
      - Franz Michael, Visiting Andrew W. Mellon Professor of History (Box 3, Folder 1.4m)
      - Psychology (Box 3, Folder 1.4n)
      - Dr. Samuel Danishefsky (Box 3, Folder 1.4o)
      - College of Arts and Sciences (CAS) (Box 3, Folder 1.4.1)
        Personnel and purpose of CAS; Proposed CAS/Business Dual Major and Proposed Undergraduate Program in Business; Physical Therapy admissions, November 29, 1978; Open House Program for CAS students as part of Parents' Weekend, August 7, 1978; and Advising Center.
      - Graduate Programs (Box 3, Folder 1.4.2)
        Distinguished Lecture Series and Dr. Elizabeth Baranger, Dean of Graduate Studies, Faculty of Arts and Sciences.
      - School of General Studies (SGS) (Box 3, Folder 1.4.3)
        SGS Graduation Dinner; Approval of SGS Saturday College, May 10, 1979; The Juvenile Justice Program with National Center for Juvenile Justice's Fifth Annual Report; Name Change for SGS, March 20, 1979; Management Study, January 30, 1979; Ligonier Valley Programming, January 16, 1979; SGS Downtown Classes, January 4, 1979; Career Seminar Series with flyers; General Studies Class Schedules, September 6, 1978; SGS Fall Promotion Campaign; SGS Annual Report, July 1, 1977 - June 30, 1978; and SGS Publications.
      - SGS - Board of Visitors (Box 3, Folder 1.4.3a)
      - Pitt's Informal Program (PIP) (Box 3, Folder 1.4.3b)
    - Graduate School of Business (GSB), 1978-1979; 1.5.
      - Correspondence and Publications (Box 3, Folder 1.5)
        Thank you letter for Dr. Posvar's participation in the recent decade of progress celebration, June 4, 1979; Associates Program of GSB with flyer; Interest in the "Productivity" Seminar, March 21, 1979; "Leadership and Education for Leadership," March 1979; GSB Advertising Campaign; and "Managing" and "Synergy" Publications.
      - GSB - General (Box 4, Folder 1.5a)
        Proposed CAS-Business Dual Major, January 1979, with Proposed Undergraduate Program in Business; The Business School and its Research Dimension and Citation Analysis Government Regulations Conference, October 31, 1978; Continuation of the services of the Greater Pittsburgh Business Development Corp. for the Office of Minority Business Enterprise, October 1978; The Pennsylvania Council on Economic Education, September 1978; Indices of Quality with "Measuring the Impact of Marketing Scholars and Institutions: Analysis of Citation Frequency," August 14, 1978; GSB Executive in Residence Program; 1978 GSB Graduation; and Booklet, Faculty Research and Publication, 1978-1980 Edition.
      - AACBS Accreditation and Self-study report (Box 4, Folder 1.5b)
      - GSB - Board of Visitors (Box 4, Folder 1.5c)
      - Center for Economic Education (Box 4, Folder 1.5d)
      - R.K. Mellon Foundation (Box 4, Folder 1.5e)
      - Dr. William Tiga Tita (Box 4, Folder 1.5f)
    - School of Education, 1978-1979; 1.6.
      - School of Education - General (Box 4, Folder 1.6)
        Recommendation on Fringe Benefits of the Faculty Council and Faculty Development Welfare Committee of the School of Education; Post Core Curriculum, January 1979; Intramural and Recreational Sports, January 19, 1979; Staff Training, December 15, 1978; Open House for the Program in Curriculum and Supervision with Descriptions of Presentations, September 1979; School of Education Parents' Weekend, August 1978; 5th Annual Colloquium sponsored by The Council of Graduate Students in Education, May 17, 1979; The 4th Annual Paul H. Masoner International Education Lecture; The 26th Annual Horace Mann Lecture, May 10, 1979; Pamphlet, Higher Education Administration Referral Service (HEARS); School of Education Alumni Newsletters, Spring 1979 and Summer 1978; and AACTE Bulletin, June 1979.
      - Board of Visitors (Box 4, Folder 1.6a)
      - Sports Medicine (Box 4, Folder 1.6b)
    - School of Engineering, 1978-1979; 1.7.
      - School of Engineering - General (Box 5, Folder 1.7)
        Letter to Thornburgh for remarks at the Engineering Alumni Annual Dinner, April 20, 1979; Emeritus Certificate for Dr. G. Raymond Fitterer with title "Dean Emeritus," March 1979; The Bradley Stoughton Award for Young Teachers of Metallurgy, March 5, 1979; Budget Policy and the Research Connection; Increased representation for the School of Engineering on the Executive Committee of the Computer Center; American Gas Association Undergraduate Grants; Major Engineering Research Grants and Contracts, December 1978; EFO Faculty Survey with Council Meeting, December 1978; Visit of Chinese Delegation of Engineering Faculty from Chiao Tung University of People's Republic of China, September 26, 1978; Minutes of Area Visit, Engineering Faculty Organization, August 2, 1978; Pittsburgh Regional Engineering Program, October 10, 1978; and Chinese Paper for UNCSTD.
      - Assistant Chancellor E.E. Bozik, "Engineering Faculty Organization Council", August 2, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 1.7a)
      - Board of Visitors (Box 5, Folder 1.7b)
      - Professor Chao-Lin Chiu (Box 5, Folder 1.7c)
      - Coal Research (Box 5, Folder 1.7d)
      - Architectural Studies (Box 5, Folder 1.7e)
      - Lightholder (Box 5, Folder 1.7f)
    - School of Law, 1978-1979; 1.8.
      - Commencement, Mellon Chair, Alumni Reunion and Budget (Box 5, Folder 1.8)
      - Board of Visitors (Box 5, Folder 1.8a)
      - National Center for Juvenile Justice (Box 5, Folder 1.8b)
    - Graduate School of Library and Information Sciences (GSLIS), 1978-1979; 1.9.
      - GSLIS - General (Box 5, Folder 1.9)
        Report from Dr. Joseph Donohue, Executive Office of the President, to GSLIS, June 1979; Approval of Undergraduate Program in Information Science and Name Change for GSLIS, June 8, 1979; Actions of the University's Board of Trustees that the name of the School be changed to the School of Library and Information Science, May 16, 1979; Comprehensive Planning Proposal, May 8, 1979; Committee on Accreditation of the American Library Association has voted to accept the 1977-1978 Annual Report of GSLIS; GSLIS Contract with U.S. Navy, December 12, 1978; 3rd Annual Pittsburgh Conference, November 6-8, 1978; Congratulations to Dean Thomas Galvin upon becoming President of the American Library Association; and Proposed Service Contract of GSLIS with Iran, July 20, 1978.
      - "SLIS: A Review of Organization and Personnel Practice" (Box 5, Folder 1.9a)
      - Board of Visitors (Box 5, Folder 1.9b)
    - Graduate School of Public and International Affairs (GSPIA), 1978-1979; 1.10.
      - GSPIA - General (Box 6, Folder 1.10.)
        Dual Degree Program in Law and Public Affairs, April 30, 1979; The National Association of Schools of Public Affairs and Administration (NASPAA) will hold its annual Conference in Pittsburgh, October 22-25, 1979; Goals for Pittsburgh Project, April 6, 1979; American Assembly on GSPIA for Pittsburgh, March 7, 1979; Report of the Institute of Training and Organizational Development; 20th Anniversary of the GSPIA, April 21, 1979; Law School/GSPIA Liaison Committee, September 30, 1978; report of John P. Robin's activities as University Professor of GSPIA and Program Advisor to the Allegheny Conference on Community Development for period July 1, 1977 to June 30, 1978; "What Should be the Optimal Size of GSPIA for the 1980s," Discussion Paper; Reasons for an Educational Renaissance; and GSPIA Flyers.
      - GSPIA - Board of Visitors (Box 6, Folder 1.10a)
      - GSPIA Student Council (Box 6, Folder 1.10b)
      - Dr. Khalid Shibli (Box 6, Folder 1.10c)
    - Graduate School of Social Work (GSSW), 1978-1979; 1.11.
      - Correspondence and Reports (Box 6, Folder 1.11)
        Revised version of Title XX grant proposal and Title XX, Social Security Act, Grants to Educational Institutions for Training; 40th Anniversary of SSW, March 29-30, 1979; Dr. Posvar asked by Allegheny County Board of Commissioners to join planning committee to prepare a long-term plan for the older residents of Allegheny County, December 1978; Analysis of the Commitment of Citizens of Pittsburgh's Neighborhoods and Policy Recommendations for City Government; and SSW - Board of Visitors.
    - Learning Research and Development Center (LRDC), 1978-1979; 1.12.
      - Site Visit Report, LRDC Coordinating Committee and Meeting with Phil Hallen (Box 6, Folder 1.12)
      - LRDC - Board of Visitors (Box 6, Folder 1.12a)
    - National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA), 1978-1979; 1.13.
      - Appropriations, Study of Pitt NASA Innovative Advanced Concepts (NIAC) and Hughes Spacecraft Program (Box 6, Folder 1.13)
    - Health Professions, 1978-1979; 1.14.
      - Health Professions - General, 1.14.
        - Reports, Correspondence and Statements (Box 6, Folder 1.14)
          Upcoming Conversation Hour of Pennsylvania Educators, June 8, 1979; Hospital Cost Control Legislation, The Administration's Proposal, May 29, 1979; Faculty Status Report; FY 1980 Budget Allocations, March 21, 1979; The Administration's Proposal, Hospital Cost Containment, March 13, 1979; Health Education Programs Proposals; Support of the Pre-hospital Emergency Care Elective (First Year), February 22, 1979; Recombinant DNA Research, February 16, 1979; Sickle Cell Program, January 1979; Proposed regulations relative to the U.S. Public Health Service "Payment for Tuition and Other Educational Costs" under authority of Section 711 of the Public Health Service Act, January 4, 1979; "Health Related Professions Week," January 21-27, 1979; Health Policy Institute; Contract for Development of Infusion Micropump, October 2, 1978; Lack of funding for Arsenal Family & Children's Center, October 2, 1978; Submission of Attached Proposal for Research to the American Iron & Steel Institute; Survey of Laboratory Animal Facilities and Resources, September 1978; and Peter Safar, M.D., awarded F.S. Cheever Distinguished Professorship for 1978/1979 and will initiate the nation's first Resuscitation Research Institute at Pitt, August 31, 1978.
        - Meeting Minutes (Box 6, Folder 1.14b)
          Committee for the Health Professions; Board of Governors of the Western Psychiatric Institute and Clinic, April 26, 1979; Medical Alumni Association, April 27, 1979; and Association of Academic Health Centers, October 7, 1978.
        - Water Supply (Box 6, Folder 1.14c)
      - School of Medicine, 1.14.1.
        - School of Medicine - General (Box 7, Folder 1.14.1)
          Non-resident applicants admitted to the School of Medicine; Richard King Mellon Charitable Trusts Endowment to School of Medicine; Donald F. Leon, M.D., lists several points which are critical for the growth of the School of Medicine, May 1, 1979; University Council on Graduate Study's evaluation on doctoral program in School of Medicine, April 3, 1979; Lois A. Pounds (Oliver), M.D., appointed Associate Dean and Director of Admissions in the School of Medicine; Policy Statement on Outside Professional Services and Consulting, March 7, 1979; Gerald S. Levey, M.D., is candidate for Chairman, Department of Medicine at Pitt's Medical School, February 27, 1979; Support of the Pre-hospital Emergency Care Elective (First Year), February 22, 1979; Organization of the School of Medicine with "An Organization Design for Better Management and Tighter Financial Control of the School of Medicine, February 1979; Grant request to Health Careers Opportunity Program of HEW to the educational enhancement of minority students, December 1978; School of Medicine Fiscal and Administrative Practices Study, December 1978; Second World Congress on Emergency and Disaster Medicine, November 1978; A public relations problem existing between the hospitals and Pitt, November 22, 1978; Minority recruitment problem, November 15, 1978; Bert W. O'Malley, M.D., Chairman, Department of Cell Biology, Baylor College of Medicine, has accepted the Dickson Prize for 1978; Proposed Allegheny College of Osteopathic Medicine and Surgery; and Psychology Department and Medical School's Racial Justice Committee.
        - Statements and Reports (Box 7, Folder 1.14.1a)
          Keynote address given at "Medical Star Trek" by Klaus Hofmann, University Professor, Protein Research Laboratory, September 1978; Gerhard Werner, M.D., has resigned as Dean, School of Medicine; Report of the Activities of The Protein Laboratory Covering the Period from September 1, 1977 to August 31, 1978, by Klaus Hofmann, Director of the Protein Research Lab; Alcoa Foundation's grant for the cardiology teaching mannequin, August 10, 1978; Annual Report of Department of Pediatrics, August 4, 1978; Faculty Scholar Award to Dr. Monte Ho, August 1, 1978; and Dr. Ephraim S. Siker appointed Professor and Chairman of the Department of Anesthesiology in the School of Medicine, July 27, 1978.
        - Task Force on the Support of Medical Education (Box 7, Folder 1.14.1b)
        - Agreement Covering School Participation in the Health Education Assistance Loan Program (Box 7, Folder 1.14.1c)
        - Proposed Actions to Achieve Resolution of Current Problems in the School of Medicine (Box 7, Folder 1.14.1d)
        - Planning for the School of Medicine (Box 7, Folder 1.14.1e)
        - To the Faculty of the School of Medicine (Box 7, Folder 1.14.1f)
        - Board of Visitors (Box 7, Folder 1.14.1h)
        - Minority Premedical Students (Summer Scholars' Program) (Box 7, Folder 1.14.1i)
        - Endicott Report (Box 7, Folder 1.14.1j)
        - Western Psychiatric Institute and Clinic (WPIC) (Box 7, Folder 1.14.1.1)
          Western Psychiatric Institute and Clinic budget, April 4, 1979; The Kresge Foundation and their grant toward expansion of library with letter listing various funding sources to WPIC; Executive Stress Program, May 7, 1979; WPIC Education & Research Center; Proposed Space for UCIR in WPIC, April 6, 1979; and Possibility of establishing a division in behavioral medicine, September 11, 1978.
        - Background for Resolution Concerning WPIC Education & Research Annex (Box 7, Folder 1.14.1.1a)
        - Letter of intent for Alcohol Research Center (Box 7, Folder 1.14.1.1b)
        - Annual Report 1977-1978, Dept of Psychiatry, University of Pittsburgh School of Medicine and WPIC (Box 8, Folder 1.14.1.1c)
        - Study of the University of Pittsburgh Costs Applicable to WPIC (Box 8, Folder 1.14.1.1d)
        - Policy of the School of Medicine on Faculty Salary Budgeting in Research Grant Applications & Disposition of Research Career Development Awards (Box 8, Folder 1.14.1.2)
        - Guidelines and Qualifications for Associate Professor and Professor in the School of Medicine (Box 8, Folder 1.14.1.2a)
        - Industry, Business and Education Verifying Need for Employee Assistance Programs (Box 8, Folder 1.14.1.2b)
        - Area Health Education Center Meeting Minutes (Box 8, Folder 1.14.1.2c)
      - Graduate School of Public Health (GSPH), 1.14.2.
        - GSPH - General (Box 8, Folder 1.14.2)
          Notice of completion of the final report Metro Wheeling Urban Study; Three students from GSPH chosen to participate in the 1979 Federal Summer Intern Program, May 2, 1979; Epidemiology Research Center, April 1979; Department Chairman, Health Services Administration, GSPH, March 14, 1979; Maternal and Child Health Program with letter from Senator Heinz; Health Policy Institute, March 20, 1979; The Thomas Parran Lectureship, December 11, 1978; Dr. David Gur appointed to membership on The Radiation Safety Committee, November 27, 1978; Mr. M. Allen Pond awarded the Sedgwick Memorial Medal, November 1978; and Memorandum of Agreement with the United Steel Workers of America, August 31, 1978.
        - Background Material (Box 8, Folder 1.14.2a)
        - GSPH - Board of Visitors (Box 8, Folder 1.14.2b)
      - Dental Medicine, 1.14.3.
        - Dental Medicine - General (Box 9, Folder 1.14.3)
          Approval of Graduate Programs, April 30, 1979; Association of Dental School Bulletin, April 1979; Special project to interest dental graduates in opening practices in rural communities, March 8, 1979; "Proposal to Establish Graduate Programs in Growth, Development and Aging, School of Dental Medicine, An Analysis" and "Proposal to Offer a Master of Dental Science Degree in Endodontics, School of Dental Medicine, An Analysis"; Change of Departmental Names; Resignation of Dean Edward J. Forrest, September 15, 1978; and Agreement Covering School Participation in the Health Education Assistance Loan Program, August 24, 1978.
        - Board of Visitors (Box 9, Folder 1.14.3a)
        - Dental School Annual Report (Box 9, Folder 1.14.3b)
      - School of Pharmacy, 1.14.4.
        - School of Pharmacy - General (Box 9, Folder 1.14.4)
          Teaching of Biochemistry to the 3rd Year Students in the School of Pharmacy, May 5, 1979; Water Analysis, April 6, 1979; Salk Hall Renovation Project, February 13, 1979; Iranian Project, November 1978; The B.S. Degree program in Pharmacy, October 10, 1978; Graduate Student Education, October 8, 1978; The Pharmacy Alumni wishes to present a bronze plaque to Dr. Posvar during half-time, September 30, 1978; Colleges or Schools of Pharmacy, Accredited Degree Programs, 1978; and Accreditation approval granted by the American Council on Pharmaceutical Education for the baccalaureate program in pharmacy.
      - School of Nursing, 1.14.5.
        - Announcements and Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 1.14.5)
          The National League for Nursing has awarded the first Davis-Taber Fellowship for Doctoral Study in Nursing to Susan Schaeffer Jay, a Doctoral Student at Pitt; The School of Nursing has received continuing accreditation for the baccalaureate and masters program in nursing; Higher Education Circular 113, "Nursing Program Moratorium," October 17, 1978; Inquiry regarding naming the School of Nursing Building Kuehn Hall in honor of the first dean, Dr. Ruth Perkins Kuehn; Development of a Charter for the Kidney Foundation of Western Pennsylvania; and Invitation to dedication of the Victoria Building with Posvar dedication remarks, October 18, 1978.
      - School of Health Related Professions (SHRP), 1.14.6.
        - SHRP - General (Box 9, Folder 1.14.6)
          Congratulatory Citation from Pennsylvania's House of Representatives on SHRP's Tenth Anniversary, May 1978; letter to Dr. Francis S. Cheever requesting that he speak on Recognition Day; Thank you letter to A.C. Van Dusen for the presentation of the proclamation of January 21-27 as Health Related Professions Week in Pittsburgh; Thank you letters to Dr. Molly T. Vogt for her service as Acting Dean of SHRP, January 1979; Arsenal Family and Children's Center has received money to remain open, October 5, 1978; and Open House at SHRP, August 9, 1978.
        - SHRP Annual Report (Box 9, Folder 1.14.6a)
        - Booklets (Box 9, Folder 1.14.6b)
        - SHRP - Board of Visitors (Box 9, Folder 1.14.6c)
    - Regional Campuses, 1978-1979; 1.15.
      - Regional Campuses - General (Box 9, Folder 1.15)
        Availability of Wilson College as a potential site for a branch campus, March 1979; Regional Campus Energy Conservation Project, November 14, 1978; Proposed Allegheny College of Osteopathic Medicine and Surgery and Proposed Osteopathic School of Medicine; Proposal for Osteopathic Medicine to be Offered by West Allegheny Hospital, June 23, 1978; and Continuation Proposal for second year funding for the Western Pennsylvania Gerontology Center, August 1978.
      - Bradford Appointment, Samuel Johnson, Dean of Instruction (Box 9, Folder 1.15.1)
      - Bradford Change to Four-year Status (Box 9, Folder 1.15.1a)
      - Greensburg (Box 10, Folder 1.15.2)
        A University Conference Center to be located at UPG, April 11, 1979; Plans to be formulated for a capital campaign, March 1979; and Public Relations, Greensburg Campus.
      - Johnstown (Box 10, Folder 1.15.3)
        Student Housing at UPJ; Johnstown Playing Field; Affirmative Action Employment at UPJ, August 1978; and "UPJ, An Overview," May 1978.
      - Titusville (Box 10, Folder 1.15.4)
        Titusville Student Union and Gymnasium and UPT Advisory Board UPT correspondence, January 1979.
      - Correspondence Regarding Possible Closure of Titusville Campus (Box 10, Folder 1.15.4a)
      - Titusville Background Papers (Box 10, Folder 1.15.4b)
      - Study of Titusville Campus (Box 10, Folder 1.15.4c)
      - Posvar Notes (Box 10, Folder 1.15.4d)
      - Pitt Evaluates Future of Titusville Campus (Box 10, Folder 1.15.4e)
      - Titusville Enrollment (Box 10, Folder 1.15.4f)
      - Response to Preliminary Planning Proposal at Titusville and an Appraisal by UPT Faculty (Box 10, Folder 1.15.4g)
      - UPT Bulletin (Box 10, Folder 1.15.4h)
      - Titusville Letters and Responses (Box 10, Folder 1.15.4i)
    - International Programs, 1978-1979; 1.16.
      - International Programs - General (Box 10, Folder 1.16)
        Follow up to Chancellors Middle East trip, June 21, 1978; Additional information on students enrolled in courses leading to the Graduate Program, June 1979; Visit of His Excellency Marian Dobrosielski, Vice Minister of Foreign Affairs, People's Republic of Poland, and Dr. S. Pawliszewski, April 18, 1979; Peace Research Studies Information Service, September 8, 1978; Israel-Pitt Relationship, August 29, 1978; and Relocation problems of the Department of East Asian Languages and Literatures within Mervis Hall, July 18, 1978.
      - International Studies Association (ISA) (Box 10, Folder 1.16a)
      - Latin American Studies (Box 11, Folder 1.16b)
      - Institute of European Studies (Box 11, Folder 1.16c)